Guide to the Gleysteen Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Gleysteen Family Papers
1842-1973
1900-1955
RG 273
Yale University Divinity School Library
21
(54 boxes)
This collection provides extensive detailed documentation of the life and work of Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen, American Presbyterian educational missionaries based in Peking (now Beijing), North China from 1905 to 1943.
Gleysteen family
Biographical / Historical
Chronology of Culver and Gleysteen families
1861 January 21 Theodore Baker Culver, father of Theodora Culver (Gleysteen), was born in Philadelphia.
1866 October 23 Annie J. Skilton Wallace (Culver), mother of Theodora Culver (Gleysteen), was born in Philadelphia.
1876 July 17 William H. Gleysteen was born in Alton, Iowa, the son of Dirk Gleysteen and Klazina van der Linden Gleysteen.
1883 Theodora Culver was born in Elkins Park, Pennsylvania, the daughter of Theodore Baker Culver and Annie Skilton Wallace Culver.
1897 William H. Gleysteen received BA from the University of Michigan after transferring from Grinnell College. He went on to complete graduate studies at Union Theological Seminary and Columbia University and was ordained in Brooklyn.
1905 William H. Gleysteen began his mission work in China, serving under the Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church. He was engaged in educational work in Peking, mainly at Truth Hall, a high school for boys, where he was Head of School, but also in organizing Presbyterian educational work throughout North China.
1907 William H. Gleysteen married Alice Carter.
1910 Alice Wilhelmina Gleysteen born, daughter of William H. and Alice Carter Gleysteen. She later married Rev. William Scott Morton of Edinburgh, Scotland.
1912 Theodore Carter Gleysteen was born, son of William and Alice Gleysteen. He later graduated from Yale in 1934.
1914 Margaret Gleysteen was born, daughter of William and Alice Gleysteen.
1916 Theodora Culver received BA from Wilson College. She went on to receive a Master's degree in history from the University of Pennsylvania.
1917 Theodora Culver began mission work in China, serving under the Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church.
1917 Alice Carter Gleysteen, wife of William Gleysteen, died in China.
1920 June William Gleysteen and Theodora Culver were married in Jenkintown, Pennsylvania.
1921 Anne Gleysteen was born, daughter of William and Theodora Culver Gleysteen.
1923 Klazina Van der Linden Gleysteen was born, daughter of William and Theodora Culver Gleysteen.
1924 Gleysteen family was on furlough in United States. Culver Gleysteen was born, son of William and Theodora Culver Gleysteen. He later graduated from Yale and was engaged in diplomatic service.
1926 William Henry Gleysteen was born, son of William and Theodora Culver Gleysteen. He later graduated from Yale in 1947.
1928 Theodore Culver, father of Theodora, died.
1930 Dirk Gleysteen was born, son of William and Theodora Culver Gleysteen.
1931 Gleysteen family was on furlough in United States following trip home from China via Europe.
1939-1940 Gleysteen family was on furlough in United States following trip home from China via Europe.
1940-1942 The Gleysteens returned to China in 1940 and were in Peking when the United States entered the war against Japan. In December 1941 Japanese soldiers surrounded the Peking compound and Gleysteens were placed under house arrest. After a time the gate guards were removed but William and the Gleysteen sons were required to wear red armbands when out in the street, indicating that they were Americans.
1943 March American and British residents in Peking were notified by Japanese authorities to go to the Civilian Assembly Center at Weihsien, Shantung (now Shandong) where the former Presbyterian compound had been made ready to receive about 1800 internees from North China. Theodora, William, William, Jr., and Dirk Gleysteen were interned at Weihsien.
1943 September Gleysteen family was among the American and Canadian citizens repatriated, leaving China on the Teia Maru and then transferring to the S.S. Gripsholm.
1944 Upon return to the United States, the Gleysteens stayed at the home of Theodora's mother in Jenkintown, Pennsylvania. William worked for the Presbyterian Board of Missions, presenting the cause of missions in the New York and Philadelphia areas.
1948 January 18 William H. Gleysteen died in Jenkintown, Pennsylvania.
1957 Annie Wallace Culver, Theodora's mother, died.
1976 May Theodora Culver Gleysteen died in Pennsylvania.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Gleysteen family, 2017
Scope and Contents
This collection provides extensive detailed documentation of the life and work of Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen, American Presbyterian missionaries based in Peking (now Beijing), North China from 1905 to 1943. The Gleysteens were engaged in educational work, primarily at Truth Hall, a high school for boys.
The collection is notable for the regular and substantive documentation that it contains. The collection centers around the family of Theodora Culver Gleysteen and includes papers related to her parents, Theodore Baker Culver and Annie Wallace Culver, thus providing a valuable longterm picture of the background and family interactions of a missionary wife, mother, and teacher during the first half of the twentieth century. Documentation of the Gleysteens' and Culvers' lives and work includes detailed, regular letters exchanged primarily with Theodora's parents, diaries, writings, memorabilia, and photographs.
In addition to his education-related work for the Board of Foreign Missions of the Presbyterian Church (USA) William Gleysteen was president of the American Association in Peking, and served as a director of Yenching University, the Peking American School, and the College of Chinese Studies. For a period he was a member of the International Famine Relief Commission.
Theodora Culver Gleysteen taught English at Truth Hall and engaged in relief work during the war in addition to being the mother of five children and three stepchildren. The Gleysteen children attended Peking American School.
Theodora and William Gleysteen and their two youngest children were interned at the Weihsien internment camp for several months in 1943.
A DVD containing digital scans of substantial portions of the documents and photographs in this collection is contained in Box 1 Folder 1.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence
II. Diaries and Notebooks
III. Writings
IV. Personal Items and Memorabilia
V. Photographs
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Missions -- China; Gleysteen, William Henry, 1876-1948; Gleysteen, Theodora Culver, 1883-1976; Gleysteen family; Gleysteen family
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Theodora Culver Gleysteen and William H. Gleysteen: family correspondence
    Scope and Contents
    The letters in this subseries are primarily from Theodora Culver Gleysteen and her husband William H. Gleysteen to Theodora's family but other correspondence and enclosures are also included as noted. The materials were taken from a series of notebook binders that were compiled by the Gleysteen family. In this subseries, the initials TCG are used to refer to Theodora Culver Gleysteen both before and after her marriage to William H. Gleysteen. The initials WHG refer to Theodora's husband William.
    - To parents from TCG; To TCG from cousin Catharine, 1904 May 9 - 1908 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Throughout this subseries "parents" refers to Theodora's parents Annie Wallace Culver and Theodore Culver. This folder also includes a DVD that contains digital scans of many documents and photographs that are in the collection.
    - TCG to parents while on trip to New Jersey; to parents from Wilson College; from mother, 1909 February 6 - 1912 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - To TCG from mother; to family from TCG at Wilson College, 1912 November 17 - 1913 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - To TCG from sister Anne, 1912 no month (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1913 October 2-18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1913 October 19 - November 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - To family from Wilson College; to Mr. Theodore B. Culver from Dwight H. Day, 1913 November 13 - December 13 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Dwight H. Day wrote on behalf of the Board of Foreign Missions, Presbyterian Church in the USA.
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1914 January 7 - March 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1914 April 13 - June 7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1914 September 15 - October 14 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1914 October 15 - November 15 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1914 November 16 - December 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College; includes letters to sister Susie, 1915 January 5 - February 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 February 9- March 10 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 March 12 - April 13 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 April 14 - May 16 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 May 17-29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College and Eagles Mere Park, PA, 1915 May 31- June 26 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 September 21 - October 22 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 October 24 - November 17 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1915 November 22-1916 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      Enclosure:"Programme of Students' Concert: Monday, December 13, 1915"
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1916 January 25 - February 6 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1916 February 7- March 19 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College, 1916 March 21 - April 19 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - To family from TCG at Wilson College; to parents during trip with sister Annie W. Culver to Vancouver, before sailing to China, 1916 April 23 - 1917 July 23 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Includes University of Pennsylvania Master of Arts acceptance letter; Theodora and Annie W. Culver were traveling to Vancouver through the Rockies before Theodora sailed to China.
    - To parents during TCG trip to Vancouver, 1917 July 24 - August 3 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - To parents during TCG's trip to Vancouver; to parents during TCG's travels to and arrival in Peking [now Beijing], 1917 August 7 - September 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking, 1917 October 10 - November 18 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking; letters from father to TCG, 1917 November 18 - 1918 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - To family from TCG in Peking; includes letters from father, 1918 February 10 - March 28 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - To family from TCG in Peking, Tsingtau, and T'ung Hsien; includes letter from father, 1918 April 2 - July 13 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - To family from TCG in T'ung Hsien; Peitaiho, and Peking; to Muzzie (Mother) from T'ung Hsien and Peking; includes letter from father, 1918 July13 - September 26 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - To family from TCG in Peking; includes letter from mother, telegram from father, 1918 October 4 - December 29 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - To family from TCG in Peking and Pang Chien, Chili Province; from William Henry Gleysteen (WHG) to Theodora's father and father's response, 1919 January 5 - March 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking, to mother from Ch'ung T'zu Nu Hsueh Hsiao (School of Gentleness, Peking); from WHG to Theodora's parents, 1919 March 4 - June 20 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking, Pang Ch'un, T'abole (Mongolia), Peitaiho; from WHG to Mr. and Mrs. Culver, 1919 June 22 - September 29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking, 1919 October 3 - December 26 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking; from WHG to Culvers from Peking, 1920 January 4 - February 22 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - To parents from TCG in Peking; to Culvers from WHG in Peking, 1920 February 28 - March 28 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - To mother from TCG in Peking; from WHG to Mrs. Culver; to Culvers from TCG and WHG during trip to United States, 1920 April 2 - August 11 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Biographical / Historical
      TCG and WHG married in June 1920 in Grace Church, Jenkintown, PA
    - To parents (Culvers) from TCG and WHG in Peitaiho and Peking, 1920 August 17 - October 3 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking, 1920 October 6 - November 14 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking, 1920 November 21 - December 29 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - From Mr. Culver to TCG; to parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to Culvers from granddaughter Alice Gleysteen in Peking, 1921 January 1 - February 12 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking, Shuntehfu; to Mrs. Culver from granddaughter Margaret Gleysteen, 1921 February 13 - March 14 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG; to Anne from TCG, WHG, and Margaret; to Culvers from grandson Theodore Gleysteen, 1921 March 18 - May 29 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to Culvers from Alice, Theodore, 1921 June 5 - August 28 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Enclosures: "Our Trip to Kalgan" and "Uncle Russell's Visit" by Theodore Gleysteen
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to sister Susie (Mrs. James C. Torrey) from TCG; from Theodore Gleysteen to WHG and TCG, 1921 September 4 - October 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; from Mr. Culver to TCG; from Theodore Gleysteen to Culvers, 1921 October 9 - 23 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; from Mr. Culver to TCG; from Alice Gleysteen, Theodore Gleysteen to Culvers, 1921 October 24 - December 29 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG at Peking; from Mr. Culver to TCG; from Alice Gleysteen to Culvers, 1922 January 1 - February 19 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; Letter to church about trip taken by TCG and school staff; to WCG from student Pai Chen Yu, 1922 February 26 - April 9 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to C.C. Steinbeck from WHG; to Culvers from Margaret, Alice, and Theodore Gleysteen; from Mr. Culver to TCG, 1922 April 16 - June 18 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peitaiho; to Elizabeth from TCG in Peking, 1922 July 2 - August 8 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Enclosure: Peking Station Report, 1921-1922
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peitaiho, Peking; to Culvers from Margaret Gleysteen; to TCG from Mr. Culver, 1922 August 22 - November 5 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Westminster Guild, Woman's Boards of Missions, PCUSA; to TCG from Mr. Culver; to Culvers from Cynthia, Alice, Theodore, 1922 October 30 - December 31 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      Enclosure: "A Christmas on a House Boat" by Alice Gleysteen
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to Culvers from Theodore Gleysteen, 1923 January 16 - March 5 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Enclosure: Report of Peking University
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking, 1923 March 18 - April 16 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Enclosure: Report of WHG for Peking Station, 1922-1923
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking and during trip to United States; to Culvers from Theodore, 1923 April 22 - October 22 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG, Theodore, Chi Nai Nai (Gleysteen's amah) during trip to United States, 1924 July 3- 12 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG during trip to United States and on way back to Peking; to Culvers from granddaughter Anne Gleysteen; to TCG from Mr. Culver, 1924 July 12-28 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG, Theodore on trip back to Peking and in Peking; telegram from Culver to Gleysteen; to Gleysteens from Clementine Bach, 1924 August 4-27 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; telegram from Culver; to Culvers from Chi Pao shih (via TCG), 1924 August 31 - October 5 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG and their children in Peking; to Annie from TCG; telegrams from Gleysteen and Culver; to TCG from Mr. Culver, 1924 October 12 - November 16 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - To Culvers from Alice, TCG, WHG in Peking, 1924 November 23 - December 14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - To Culvers from TCG, Theodore, Margaret, WHG, Alice in Peking, 1924 December 14-28 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to TCG from Mr. Culver, 1925 January 4 - February 7 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - To Katie Culver (aunt) and Culvers from WHG, TCG, Alice, Theodore in Peking; to TCG from Mr. Culver; to Mrs. Culver from Chi Pao shih, 1925 February 8 - March 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to TCG from unidentified, 1925 March 7 - April 24 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG, Alice in Peking; to TCG from Mr. Culver, 1925 May 2-31 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking, Peitaiho, 1925 June 7- July 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - To Culvers from TCG, Alice, Theodore in Peitaiho, 1925 July 7-25 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Enclosure: "A Trip to Pei Niu Ting"
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peitaiho; to Annie from TCG, 1925 August 2 - September 4 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - To parents from TCG, WHG in Peking, 1925 September 6 - November 4 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - To Culvers from WHG, Theodore, TCG in Peking; from Mr. Culver to TCG; to WHG from F.K. Jowe, 1925 November 7 - December 6 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Enclosure:"Relief for the Poor" by Fei Chi Ghun
    - To Culvers from TCG, Alice, WHG, Anne, Margaret in Peking; to TCG from Mr. Culver; to Mrs. Culver from Chi Pao-shih, 1926 January 1 - February 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking, 1926 February 3 - April 22 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG, Alice in Peking, 1926 April 25 - June 3 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG, Margaret, Alice, Anne, in Peking, Peitaiho; to Culvers from Alice in Korea and Japan, 1926 June 6 - July 28 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - To Culvers from TCG, WHG, Alice, Anne in Peking and Peitaiho, 1926 August 1 - November 24 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - To parents from TCG and WHG in Peking; to WHG from Chin Wen Yi, 1926 November 25 - December 30 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Enclosures: "Should Religious Worship and Instruction be Compulsory?" by Hwang Tz Sheu; "A Thanksgiving Prayer", "The Bible Class of T'ze Yiin Kung Ching"
    - To parents from TCG, WHG in Peking; to TCG from Mr. Culver; to Annie Heacock from Helen Scott; to Annie from TCG, 1927 January 9 - February 26 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - To parents from TCG, WHG in Peking; to Culvers from TCG in Osaka; to TCG from Mr. Culver, 1927 February 27- December 20 (Box 6, Folder 11)
      Enclosure: "Personal Report of WHG-1927"
    - To parents from TCG, WHG in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Theodore, WHG in Peking, 1928 March 4 - April 15 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG and TCG in Peking, 1928 April 22 - June 21 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - To WHG from TCG in Kaifengfu, etc.; to Margaret from TCG in Hangchow; to Mrs. Culver from TCG in Peking, Peitaiho, 1929 January 29 - July 21 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Margaret, Klazina, Theodore in Peitaiho, Peking; to Mrs. Culver from Theodore C. Greene, from Alice in Iowa, 1929 July 22 - September 22 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG in Peking; to TCG from Elizabeth McCoy, 1929 September 22 - November 3 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Alice at Smith College; to Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne in Peking, 1929 November 4 - December 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Enclosure:"Statement by the China International Famine Relief Commission concerning the report of the American Red Cross Delegation to China"
    - To Annie from Helen Scott at Peking; to Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Klazina in Peking, 1929 December 4-31 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Chi Pao-Shuh in Peking; to Mrs. Culver from WHG, Klazina, TCG in Peking, 1930 January 3 - February 3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Klazina in Peking; "News Bulletin No. 1", 1930 February 3 - April 20 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      "News Bulletins" and "Bulletins" noted here and below are circular-type report letters sent out by the Gleysteens. Enclosure: "Personal Report of Theodora Culver Gleysteen 1930"
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Klazina, Anne in Peking; "Weekly Bulletin: April 21st, 1930"; "News Bulletin" Nos. 2, 3, 4, 1930 April 20 - May 25 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Enclosures: "Personal Report of Wm. H. Gleysteen, May, 1930"; "The Ringing of the Bell" by George C. Chang
    - To Mrs. Culver from Margaret, TCG, WHG, Alice, Klazina in Peking, Peitaiho; to Aunt Mamie from TCG; "Bulletin" Nos. 5, 6, 8, 9,10; Ashbourne Order for Mrs. Culver and letter to Aunt Mamie from TCG, 1930 May 27- July 3 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne in Peitaiho; "Bulletin" Nos. 11, 13, 14, 15, 1930 July 6 - Augist 19 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - To Mrs. Culver from A.H. Mateer, from TCG, WHG in Peitaiho, Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 15, 16, 17, 19; "News Bulletin: August 31, 1930"; "TCG's Bulletins", 1930 August 24 - September 21 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG in Peking; "TCG's Bulletins"; "Bulletin" Nos. 20, 23, 24, 25, 26; to Aunt Mamie from TCG, 1930 September 28 - November 3 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Enclosures: "Peking Union Church Bulletin: October, 1930"; "Financial Statement of Dealings Between Industrial School Peking and Mrs. Culver per Theodora"; "Financial Statement of Dealing between Industrial School, Peking and Mrs. A.S. Miller, per T.C. Gleysteen"
    - To Mrs. Culver from Theodore at Grinnell College; to Mrs. Culver from TCG, Klazina, WHG, Anne in Peking, 1930 November 8 - December 31 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Enclosures: Armistice Sunday Service Bulletin, Nov. 9, Peking Union Church; Peking Union Church Christmas Musical Service Bulletin
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Culver in Peking;; "Bulletin - Second Series" Nos. 1, 2, 1931 January 4 - February 18 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      Enclosure: Peking Union Church bulletin, January 18
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Anne in Peking; "Bulletin" Nos. 3, 4, 5; "Family Bulletin: March 29, 1931", 1931 February 22 - March 29 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Billy (William H., Jr.), TCG, WHG, Klazina, Anne in Peking; "Bulletins", 1931 April 5 - May 17 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Enclosures: "Personal Report of Theodora Culver Gleysteen, April 1931"; "Personal Report of Wm. H. Gleysteen, May 2nd, 1931"
    - To Mrs. Culver from Anne, TCG, WHG, Klazina in Peking; "Bulletin", 1931 May 23 - June 28 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Margaret, TCG, Anne, WHG in Peking and on way to United States; to Gleysteens from churches/schools for a farewell service, 1931 July 2 - August 16 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Enclosure: itinerary of SS Saarbrucken
    - To Mrs. Culver from WHG, TCG, Klazina, Alice from SS Saarbrucken and Geneva, Switzerland, 1931 August 23 -September 19 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG, Klazina, Margaret, Anne in Switzerland and Germany, 1931 September 25 - October 17 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - To Mrs. Culver from Alice, WHG, TCG, Anne in Germany, Paris, Amsterdam, London, 1931 October 19 - December 26 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - To Mrs. Culver from TCG, WHG on way back to China, 1932 March 20 - August 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Enclosure: "Who Am I?" by Chen Chun